<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>slightly toasty arnibal</title>
    <description>Mid 20s word vomit
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 14:04:35 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 14:04:35 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Two more</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I once made a comment in the PKPH group about how I felt more like a spectator than a traceuse when we train. For the last two weeks of March I didn’t really feel like going to bansay. Towards the end of the month I tend to get discouraged about my progress and I start to wonder whether what I’m putting my time into is really paying off. Funny, what saved me from balking was our venue permit. I had volunteered to be the contact person for UP Diliman. I felt obliged to attend since I was already the person talking to the guards there. I also posted about showing up to parkour a few weeks ago. While only a handful of people really know about this blog, I didn’t want to eat my words either. So I forced myself to show up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brain was in a slump, I didn’t think showing up twice in two weeks would make a difference. I’m happy to be proven wrong. Over the past few weeks I’ve developed a love/hate relationship with walls. I’ve grown to like flopping down on the grass and rising up with bits of dried leaves clinging to my clothes. I even wanted to roll in the stuff after a grueling set of push ups. I forgot about counting jumps, vaults, distances covered. I stopped quantifying so much in my training log. I described more. I imagined rocks as giant chunks of red jello that would splatter into a gooey mess if I landed loudly. One midnight, I found myself doing ground kongs in the middle of writing a paper outside (afterwards my sister had to ask why I was typing with such filthy hands). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recall getting annoyed at repeatedly encountering various ways of people saying “you can’t know parkour unless you’ve done it”. But I had to agree. I also remember reading a lot about training alone, and being skeptical about the hype. But, heck, that one’s also true. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since it was the end of March I finally trained alone to film my month’s progress. I had wanted to do this since February because I figured I’m only going to be new at this once. I wanted to capture my awkwardness with the goal of contrasting it to next month’s progress. I had asked Joles a few weeks back how she got the guts to train alone and she told me music and earphones really helped. Given my oblivious nature, that sounded like an accident already. So I just wore a pair of my earbuds without pumping any music. This really helped, haha. Earbuds without music are awesome for pretending not to give a fuck. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…Which surprisingly, I did not give much of to begin with. I just wanted to roll and jump. And climb. Perhaps it takes that little nudge to stop being a spectator. The moment when wanting to move overpowers the fear of being looked at and judged. It’s not even proper to describe it as overpowering, caring about doing a weird roll just faded into the background. Perhaps you participate in parkour the moment you can laugh at yourself, the moment when you legitimately start longing to move. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels more authentic now, referring to myself as a traceuse. Two months ago I hated rolls. Last bansay I wanted to do them. Forward, even left and right without even being told how to. I’m still working on my backward rolls as I never managed to get those right. But I find I don’t mind trying and failing (so long as it doesn’t hurt!) so much. I don’t feel lost during playtime. I even tried a bit of capoeira. And that makes me happy, that I’m beginning to warm up to failure. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote this because wanting to give up on parkour is legit. This is probably not the last time I’ll feel this way. But the next time I do, I’ll give it two more weeks, maybe two more months. It took me that long to relearn how to play, who knows what else will surprise me. &lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2015 21:18:20 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/traceuse/2015/04/11/two-more.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/traceuse/2015/04/11/two-more.html</guid>
        
        <category>traceuse,</category>
        
        <category>parkour</category>
        
        
        <category>traceuse</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Becoming Here-ists</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;I was supposed to write here weekly. But I noticed I’ve been writing too much about parkour. Here’s a reflection paper I wrote about orientalism in Philippine architecture instead. I like starting reflection papers because it’s initially rambling, but having to organize my thoughts eventually into understandable text is hard work for me. I got good feedback on this one though so I guess it’s worth posting. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the debate in class, of which my role was a neutral spectator, one of the key take-aways was that the orientalism depends a lot on which viewpoint we are coming from. Our contemporary architecture was presented as mimicking or holding importance to western styles of architecture, while the opposing argument was that this is a mere inevitable product of globalization. My general opinion on this is that while these are both valid, the majority of Philippine society still holds the orientalist view. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also hold the opinion that this view is still held today out of ignorance. There are three modes I observed, from experience and from points in the debate, in which the orientalist view persists today: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) The purism viewpoint, where we exclude and deem all foreign influence as un-Filipino
2.) The thoughtless and unfeeling use of Filipino symbols or motifs just for the sake of labeling something Filipino
3.) The standard “western is better” viewpoint&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purism viewpoint is the tendency to categorize Filipino architecture as Filipino only if it is reminiscent of pre-colonial architecture or veers away from foreign influence. The example presented in class was how a typical Filipino household will buy a banga or bulul to add Filipino accents to their home because these are indigenous. This is also related to the point raised in the first argument stating how Filipino architecture is always being reduced to the bahay kubo. There is also this strong reaction against architecture influenced by foreign cultures. When I read how there was unauthorized construction in Manila at the cultural heritage building, the El Hogar, I remember reading the author explaining the importance of the building in our culture because of its history. At the time, I found myself thinking, well that’s a given! The thing is that many people still view these types of buildings as unwanted products of our colonization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This view is orientalist because this is still a form of “othering”. When we “purify” by separating what is not pre-colonial, we are defining ourselves relative to a foreign influence. This is similar to how our national language went through a purist phase where they had to invent words that did not catch on in everyday use because you cannot force culture – it’s dynamic and a random collective effort of society. This mentality is damaging because it hinders our art and architecture from catching up to our real culture, our present one, which has adapted and evolved in real time to events and circumstances we have experienced. We can still appreciate the indigenous and original, but to get past this viewpoint, we have to celebrate and create new Filipino architecture. By being innovative and exposing our society to new and good architecture, the benefits of new styles will slowly be accepted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second viewpoint is similar to the first one. The difference is that unlike the first viewpoint focused on authenticity and purity in the classification of things that are Filipino, this one makes a point to make everything Filipino, even when there is no need to do so (because, you know, things can just inherently be Filipino). This was touched on during the debate in how symbols or motifs that are indigenous or rural to us are blatantly slapped on to anything to instantly make it Filipino. This is what was argued in class as reducing our culture to the baro’t saya. An everyday example of this is along Boni Serrano Avenue, when you look at their railings, they’re the standard street divider but in the middle of the grille-work is a man with a salakot and other Filipino motifs. I also agree that our pavilions in the past (again, the salakot, and even those tiki motifs) were guilty of this, being too literal and unsubtle in trying to communicate our culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I appreciate these examples though, because they are attempts. And as Noel said in class, if we identify with the baro’t saya, then that’s us as a culture.Maybe being tacky with salakot motifs is part of our culture. But again I still find this orientalist because it limits what Filipino culture is. It identifies things as not Filipino then haphazardly slaps on a salakot or two to make it so. It comes off as insecure. Which is understandable because we really are still insecure about our culture. The remedy to this is to study ourselves, and identify what really makes us Filipino, past the rattan, bamboo, and baro’t saya. Let’s look at and immerse ourselves in the intangible aspects of our culture. Then we should simply stop trying so hard to make Filipino architecture, and like the Philippine artist movement, simply create the best architecture we are capable of, because our values and aspirations as a culture will inevitably show through these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there’s the prevalent colonial-mentality viewpoint where we feel that modern, mostly western, is better. This is a tricky one because even I become guilty of this without meaning to. As mentioned in class, it’s difficult to get out of brainwashing. I’ve seen this even in my UP educated friends who I consider nationalistic and discerning. While we were walking around Teacher’s Village helping a friend look for lodging, they would point out modern-looking houses to me (their architecture student friend), telling me how they would like a house like that or how beautiful the building was. If I hadn’t studied this for 1.5 years already I would have probably agreed. Instead I would always reply how yes, it looked cool, but I would point to another house saying I liked this roof better, or how that one had more operable windows. It’s very real how we take in a lot of influences because of their aesthetics (in Micah’s words, “pinapatong lang”) even when they are not of practical use to us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also agree with the rebuttal and argument that the modern look of our architecture is just a natural effect of globalization. New information and technology is a boon to us. If we are to make resilient homes for our typhoon ridden climate for example, foreign information is welcome. But the key here is to be more discerning and not take everything at face value. Filipino architects must never solely depend on outside information but also make our own research, come up with styles, that are relevant to our society. When we take outside influence, we have to look at how these are useful to us as Filipinos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In ending the debate, Ronn pointed out how much the discussion revealed how this was more of a problem of awareness. This is true because most of how I think orientalistm can be removed from our architecture involves education or a change of mindset. We were asked what we can do to take part in solving the problem in terms of spreading awareness. I think one of the ways with a low barrier to entry we can do as a generation is by spreading awareness through social media. If it’s so easy to snap a shot and say something about a couple doing PDA behind you, so is posting a 140-character critique of this ugly building you just walked by. This is a small step we can take into becoming here-ists and shifting our viewpoint back to the Philippine perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2015 04:33:20 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/arki/2015/03/22/becoming-here-ists.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/arki/2015/03/22/becoming-here-ists.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>arki</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The day after bansay</title>
        <description>&lt;center&gt;
Me, when I wake up: &lt;br /&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150309-IveBeenWaitingForThisPain.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;I&#39;ve been waiting for this pain&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;


&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;



When I climb onto a jeep:  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150309-HurtMeMore.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hurt me more!&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;


&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;



When I reach for a book on a high shelf:  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150309-MoreMore.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;More! More!&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;


&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;



When I have no choice but to climb the stairs:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150309-Eeeyaaaaah.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Eeeyaaaaah!&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; /&gt;


&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

._.  
  
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Gray Fox lines echo in my head the day after bansay. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

It is known.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;




Images grabbed from &lt;a href=&quot;http://youtu.be/XBzfERq-kBc&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;.

&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 03:10:20 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/traceuse/2015/03/10/me-the-day-after-bansay.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/traceuse/2015/03/10/me-the-day-after-bansay.html</guid>
        
        <category>traceuse</category>
        
        <category>parkour</category>
        
        
        <category>traceuse</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>IWD2015: Showing up to Parkour</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2004, I was reading through my brother’s pile of Global Frequency comic books by Warren Ellis. Issue 6, “The Run”, featured frequency agent 992 – a &lt;i&gt;Le Parkour&lt;/i&gt; expert residing in London. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150308-TheRun.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Global Frequency 6&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150308-Sita.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Global Frequency 6&quot; width=&quot;250&quot; /&gt;  


&lt;br /&gt;
	&lt;i&gt;Sita Patel jumps to save London. Images from the issue preview you can read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.readdcentertainment.com/Global-Frequency-6-of-12/digital-comic/0312900065001&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.**&lt;/i&gt;

&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back on it, it was pretty neat that my first exposure to parkour was from the POV of a traceuse saving London from bio-terrorists. A few months later my brother also made me watch B13. I only found out a decade later, 2014, who David Belle is.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 10-year span where I associated parkour with fiction, Leïto and Sita were the only parkour practitioners I could recall. In my head, traceuses were a norm. I guess that’s why it surprised me when I attended my first ever parkour session that I was the only woman there (though later in the session another woman joined us!). So months later, when I heard that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/parkourphilippines&quot;&gt;PKPH&lt;/a&gt; had a female-focused &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.parkourphilippines.org/articles/pkphbansay-parkour-sunday-training-rules-and-regulation&quot;&gt;bansay&lt;/a&gt; in the works I was giddy-excited looking forward to it.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know female-only training sessions are a touchy subject, even in the international parkour community. There are some who believe segregating women during parkour training is unnecessary, even to the extent of saying it will hamper the growth of parkour. My view on this is…&lt;i&gt;I honestly don’t see why this is such a big deal&lt;/i&gt;. In any activity dominated by a gender, people of the minority gender will naturally form groups. Because, &lt;i&gt;possibly&lt;/i&gt;, they experience the activity differently in some ways and seek people whose experiences they can relate to. Human and natural. That’s why there are groups for male knitters. And no, I don’t think that’s hampering the growth of the knitting community. There are even more examples outside of gender differences.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I was happy to attended our first female-focused session for PKPH Bansay today. The women and girls, most of whom are new to parkour, had different drills and playtime split from the male regulars. How was it and how did I find it different from the usual bansay?&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of it was as I imagined. We were new, built more similarly, and most of us had little athletic background. It felt somewhat reassuring that I wasn’t the only one having a hard time with tucks. I wasn’t the only one with hurt shoulders from practicing rolls. It was refreshing to look around and see facial expressions mirroring mine.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the differences led to realizations on how I view or react to situations during training.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was having difficulty with a drill, I felt less frustrated about it. I found it easier to ask for help, even repeating precisions to ask someone what went wrong. In the past whenever I was reassured by leads that they also took time to get a skill right, there was still a lot of self-doubt because I was the only one not getting it right! But this time around, my group shared in the struggle, so I understood better.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also realized that when I have questions or want to learn something I usually only approach the community members who have lead the bansay. Since the experienced women in the community were training leads for this session, I found myself approaching them more to ask about my form or technique. I’m usually in the beginner’s group during regular sessions, training separately from intermediate traceuses, so this was a really welcome change.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also this subtle shift in mindset in doing it right vs not doing it wrong. From the past drills sessions, I realized I focused so much, even worried, on not doing a drill wrong. Because I had been attending bansay the longest in my group (since February), I was somehow obliged to initiate with the drills after the training leads finished explaining and demonstrating the correct technique. I felt like it was on me to show my group that it could be done. It’s like a shift in motivation to get it right. You could call it big-sister syndrome.  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it was different but a really fun session! I remembered how to play! And I learned a lot, not just in skill but in the way I view training. But perhaps because it was an introductory bansay, I’d have to agree when Chela mentioned that it was milder than the usual training session. I missed the fear that usually comes with bansay, and the elation that comes after conquering it. Maybe because I’ve already gotten over some of the little fears that my new sisters in parkour had just conquered today. At the end of the day, I feel I can learn a lot from both types of sessions. Training with other practitioners, regardless of gender, but of other skill levels also challenges you and exposes you to the possibilities of parkour. So I also hope to see my fellow traceuses in the regular bansay sessions.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to today’s bansay, I recently joined &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/girlsacross/&quot;&gt;Parkour Girls Across&lt;/a&gt;, and one of the questions raised there was how to get more women to practice parkour. It seems that all over the world, traceuses are also finding it hard to get other women into parkour. What I’ve noticed from these past six weeks of training is that I’ve often been asked by fellow beginner traceuses whether I’d be at the next bansay. I think a lot of women decided to join today’s International Women’s Day bansay because of the reassurance there would be other women whom they could share the experience with and relate to.** I’m the same. I became friends with others new to parkour faster. I felt more compelled to try parkour again because I saw other women doing parkour. I’m grateful for the PKPH community as a whole, but I have a special heartfelt thanks reserved for Chela, Joles, Lady and Sacha for showing up consistently to bansay and appearing on the PKPH Facebook page. While I can dream of being a badass like Sita Patel, these women are my real life inspiration. That said, what’s a beginner traceuse to do? How can I help get more female representation in parkour?  I can pay the favor forward. I’ll show up.&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;    &lt;br /&gt;    &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT 03/10/2015:  &lt;br /&gt;
** Oh yeah! Global Frequency is getting another shot at a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.comicbookresources.com/?page=article&amp;amp;id=57295&quot;&gt;tv series&lt;/a&gt;. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*** Just saw this &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.myfitnesspal.com/the-surprisingly-simple-enjoyable-way-to-make-weight-loss-stick/&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; describing a bit of Social Cognitive Theory. Maybe what I’m trying to describe is related to the Vicarious Experience model on trying new things. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2015 04:16:20 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/traceuse/2015/03/09/iwd2015-showing-up-to-parkour.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/traceuse/2015/03/09/iwd2015-showing-up-to-parkour.html</guid>
        
        <category>traceuse</category>
        
        <category>parkour</category>
        
        <category>womanhood</category>
        
        
        <category>traceuse</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>KMC Perfect Hyper Mats</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;I’m still learning how to use Jekyll. I need to get the hang of posting pictures so this is a picture post. Sorry for the blurry pictures. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I found myself volunteering to do a tedious task. De-sleeving 185 cards. Then sleeving 191 cards. Twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brother came home with Haggatha the Heffer’s Crushazorian Godstorm and several packs of KMC Hyper Mat Clear and KMC Perfect Size sleeves.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…I’m really just the type to get excited over really nice card sleeves. TvT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150307-HaggathaSpell.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Haggatha the Heffer&#39;s Crushazorian Godstorm&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150307-Haggatha.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Haggatha the Heffer&#39;s&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150307-KMCSleeves.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Card &amp;quot;barriers&amp;quot; instead of sleeves sound cooler really&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150307-PerfectSizeInstructions.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Perfect Size Instructions&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at how the Perfect Size sleeves are supposed to work! What the hell KMC. That’s like the HG of sleeves. So stupid and delightful at the same time. Perhaps that’s why I relate to these sleeves so much. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150307-Desleeving.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Some cards and their old sleeves&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I removed the old card sleeves. These are just freebie sleeves that came with the game. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150307-SleevesComparisonShot.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A comparison shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a comparison shot of the Hyper Mat Clear, the Perfect Size and the old sleeves. You can tell Perfect Size is much smaller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150307-OberonSleeves.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;King Oberon is a strange looking wizard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;King Oberon with Perfect Size and Hyper Mat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150307-PerfectSizeSleeving.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Slide em into Perfect Size!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was pretty hard at first to slide cards into the Perfect Sizes. I discovered holding them like this and pushing with your pointy fingers was pretty effective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150307-HyperMatSleeving.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Into the Hyper Mats you go&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turned upside down and into the Hyper Mats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150307-FrontSleeved.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;So cutie clear la&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cutie clear at the front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150307-BackSleeved.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Matte so your spells don&#39;t slide. My hips don&#39;t lie.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matte at the back. So nice! Opaques would also have been cool, but even the back of the cards are pretty epic (oh pun!) in this game so the Hyper Mat Clears are perfect. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150307-AllSleeved.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;All done!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Done with the rest of 190 cards! Had to press on them gently because air was trapped inside each double sleeved card. Mt. Skullzfyre at the back! ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150307-Cards.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Yes! They Fit. &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150307-Box Content.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Even with Mt. Skullzfyre&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/20150307-ClosedBox.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The end.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glad they still fit in the box even with the extra padding. My brother accidentally sat on the box hence the torn cover. How wizardly.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah, I love KMCs. I found the tediousness pretty nostalgic. It’s awesome they’re now readily available here. I only have the Super Orange sleeves from back in fifth grade, and we even had to go to that shady Tsuen Wan mall to get them. They now sit in the dark hugging my old Pokemon cards. Ah memories.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epic Spell Wars of the Battle Wizards: Duel at Mt. Skullzfyre is probably the most played table top game in our household so I’m super glad the cards are now doubly sleeved. I heard this game didn’t get great reviews initially, so I might as well leave a short review. If you’re looking for a game with strategy, calculation, thinking 5 steps ahead.. then don’t play Epic Spell Wars. This game is not for tryhards. Sure you can do those things but this game is just too epic (oh here I go again sorry) those tactics randomly explode in your face. You still need to think about your spells though, so it’s not entirely a mindless game. The game design, the random elements, flavor text, and the art direction really make you feel like you’re in a wizard battle. It reminds us of the Wizard Battle episode in Adventure Time season 3, only more action packed. Only wizards allowed!  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s best played, in my opinion, with four wizards. Above that, you get pretty restless waiting for the battle to end if you were killed off early in the game. Kuya sent us a heads up that &lt;a href=&quot;https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/173200/epic-spell-wars-battle-wizards-rumble-castle-tenta&quot;&gt;Epic Spell Wars II: Rumble at Castle Tentakill&lt;/a&gt;, is in the works though, hopefully they improved that side of the game. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Mar 2015 18:54:20 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/tabletop/2015/03/07/kmc-perfect-hyper-mats.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/tabletop/2015/03/07/kmc-perfect-hyper-mats.html</guid>
        
        <category>tabletop</category>
        
        <category>things</category>
        
        
        <category>tabletop</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Playground days</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It just sunk in how conditioning is such a big chunk of parkour. It has also sunk in how much I’ve been in avoidance of it. Back in January, I found a beginner routine which I had planned on doing twice a week. I thought buying equipment this early on would be overkill, so I designated two playground days to do the routine per week. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hated the playground days. I felt extremely exposed whenever I do them. So along the way I fell off and did some other bullshit conditioning at home. Over the weekend, I somehow convinced myself that going out alone to train in a public space is a necessary part of parkour. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I tried again today. I started with inclined push-ups near the see-saws and rows near the monkey bars. An old man came over to use the monkey bars for exercise but he was far enough from my space that I could still proceed with my reps. I was going through my last set when another old man came over to talk to his friend at the monkey bars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;     &lt;i&gt;“Oh, ang galing naman ng kasama mo, nag e-exercise.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The comments were obviously directed at me. What was so great about this? They were all doing some sort of exercise themselves. It was annoying but I just wanted to finish my reps. At the fifth rep, my arms needed a break so I plopped down on the sand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;     &lt;i&gt;“O, masakit yun ah.”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not. :/   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finishet my set, stood up to write my numbers in my notebook, which had a brown leather cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;     &lt;i&gt;“Ano binabasa niya, bibliya?”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ugh. Fortunately that was the last set of rows I needed. I tried to be stoic about it, just ignored everything, and walked away to a bench to do lunges. I wonder if I should have been more sociable, but I’ve spent too much time on Tumblr and felt like I wouldn’t have received side comments if I were a guy. From afar I saw people letting their dogs poop in the playground sandbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finished a second set of foot-assisted pull ups. My arms were getting sore. Looked around to check for a place to do dips. The woman who was jogging I exchanged smiles with had left. To my right, the couple with their poopy puppy remained. Far to my left was the group of old men, bantering. The sun had risen and it was getting hot. Behind me, a man was sitting at the playground wall wearing a jacket and a beanie. I didn’t feel like doing dips anymore. I wrote in my notebook and left.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They say parkour is also about reclaiming urban space. I recall a past lecture on how architecture isn’t limited to the built environment. Place-making involves a person’s feelings and memories tied to a space. Frankly, my feelings about the playground suck right now. There’s also the cultural aspect of being raised as a woman in the Philippines, being told not to go out alone, magpasama ka, etc. There’s this constant nagging at the back of my head that I shouldn’t be somewhere which changes the way I view a space. But I also recall Paulo Alcazaren’s words last week, on how graveyards and golf courses have become the majority of open spaces in Metro Manila. Small islands of open space like this playground need to be protected from public nuisance. Perhaps as a traceuse, I need to show up in this space in order to claim it. :/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m going to report unpeople having their dogs use the playground as a litter box. But I feel mildly defeated. Should I have said something to the couple? Or politely explained what I was doing to an annoying old man? Should I bring plastic bags and our extra pooper scooper next time and lend it to people? What would Epictetus have done? Is this the social side of being strong to be useful?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Game is hard.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;    &lt;br /&gt;    &lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT 03/10/2015:  &lt;br /&gt;
Well today was playground day. Game is NOT hard. Gawd I want to delete this post. Let this serve as an example of what happens when I miss my weekend stoic meditation. What would Epictetus have done? He would have side-eyed me. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 18:47:20 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/parkour,/arki,/traceuse/2015/03/03/playground-days.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/parkour,/arki,/traceuse/2015/03/03/playground-days.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>parkour,</category>
        
        <category>arki,</category>
        
        <category>traceuse</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>This lifestyle change thing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I was diagnosed with PCOS and prescribed birth control pills to manage my symptoms when I was 23. While PCOS isn’t a life threatening condition, it’s an endocrine disorder with symptoms that are &lt;i&gt;super annoying&lt;/i&gt;. Later, I found out that pills (I was on Yaz) were just masking my symptoms and not really managing the cause of my PCOS. I did not see myself gulping them down everyday in the future. What if I have to stop taking them when I’m older because of the link to cardiovascular risk? I didn’t think I was doing myself a favor by being dependent on medication. So I weaned myself off slowly last year (took me 3 months) and at 26, I’m pill-free again. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the slightly harder part. Since I’m now off the synthetic estrogen and progesterone, I have to deal with whatever crap they masked for the past two and a half years. Just about two months of being off, I already have the acne and hair loss returning. Back with all the other symptoms that never went away while on medication, like my skin tag, acanthosis nigricans, and the so-called PCOS belly. There’s no one treatment for PCOS because each woman has a unique body – each one’s lifestyle and genetics are only some of the factors that play out in our body’s intricate chemical signaling. I don’t think BCPs are one-size fits all. The only way I can deal is to figure out the particular healthy lifestyle that my body wants me to live. With diet, I already improved some of the symptoms, like the lethargy and constant brain fog. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far here are some changes  I’ve been playing with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;u&gt;Diet&lt;/u&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
 -switched to generally low GI diet&lt;br /&gt;
 -switched white or highly refined carbs to lower glycemic load alternatives (black rice instead of white rice)&lt;br /&gt;
 -No more sugar in my coffee&lt;br /&gt;
 -Limiting coffee to once per day&lt;br /&gt;
 -Avoiding inflammatory food that might disrupt my already disrupted hormones like dairy&lt;br /&gt;
 -Became suspicious of things that list vegetable oils in the ingredients&lt;br /&gt;
 -Feel weird about eating out because they probably cook everything in cheap veggie oil&lt;br /&gt;
 -Experimenting with resistant starch (potato starch)&lt;br /&gt;
 -Cut out soda since January and have stopped craving them finally. If I feel like having a flavored drink, I drink green tea&lt;br /&gt;
 -When craving sugar started choosing the lesser evil (eating a banana instead of that Conti’s leche flan D:)&lt;br /&gt;
 -Only drink wine and beer if it’s free&lt;br /&gt;
 -Learned to cook and take healthier meals to school&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Exercise&lt;/u&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
 -Try to get 3 hours resistance work per week   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Sleep&lt;/u&gt;:&lt;br /&gt;
 -Try to get 7.5 hours per day&lt;br /&gt;
 -Trying not to nap so I don’t sleep late  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Everyday things&lt;/u&gt;: &lt;br /&gt;
 -Try to minimize exposure to xenoestrogens&lt;br /&gt;
 -Become paranoid and wary about plastic cooking utensils&lt;br /&gt;
 -Switched to a more natural laundry powder (the smell of normal laundry soap now nauseates me. I can’t borrow clothes from my siblings who still use them)&lt;br /&gt;
 -Switched to stainless steel baunan and bottle  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve gotten rid of the constant brain fog when I cut out sugar, and gained more clarity when I tried the potato starch. See, I can even write things like these now! I’m still experimenting with what I can eat. I pay closer attention to how I feel after eating certain foods and try to eliminate things my face reacts to. I guess that’s a good thing about my acne, it has turned into some weird-food-reaction indicator. I ate some beef the other day and it did not like it. Blared up all red and itchy. Thanks face. I guess you were warning me it was some CAFO meat chock-full of hormones that I should never eat again. Seriously considering if I can go pescetarian now, since I can’t afford organic beef or pork while on a student budget. (I’ve been allergic to chicken since childhood.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another general suggestion for PCOS is exercise. I’ve read that strength or resistance training is probably best. I haven’t had my levels tested recently but I suspect I’m estrogen dominant. A lot of estrogen is stored in fat cells. Maybe if I gain muscle mass and reduce the ratio even a tiny bit, that could help? I have never really worked out except in conditioning for PE and other recreational activities I joined with friends so I am clueless about strength training. I didn’t really see myself exercising just for the sake of exercise, so I decided on an activity last year that I could improve at by myself (as opposed to activities like football or kendo) which happened to be parkour. I’m not sure if it’s just the exercise-induced endorphins, but I’m super happy I joined the weekly PKPH bansay. Being exposed to strong people regularly makes you want to do more negative push-ups and box jumps. I’m still struggling with meeting the three-hour weekly quota but I feel pretty happy with this area, having been a former couch potato.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be TMI past this point. I’ve read a lot of horror stories on the forums where BCP ruined women’s menstrual cycles, some, even for years. After weaning, I was slightly worried because my period came back after a whopping 93 days. It’s recommended that women shed their uterine lining every three months to prevent risk of endometriosis or other complications. If my period comes that late again, I might have to get synthetic progesterone prescribed just to induce the shedding, when I didn’t want to depend on medication in the first place. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But after a whole month of exercise and a better diet, my cycle returned to 42 days, which was close to the average before I was diagnosed. The flow is not as light as it was while I was on BCP, but it’s not painful. So I’m pretty excited about continuing with this. I’m still monitoring symptoms though, and if I feel like I haven’t made enough improvement by June, I plan to see a reproductive endocrinologist to get some specifics on where to go from here. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2015 23:22:20 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/pcos/2015/03/02/this-lifestyle-change-thing.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/pcos/2015/03/02/this-lifestyle-change-thing.html</guid>
        
        <category>PCOS</category>
        
        <category>life</category>
        
        <category>experiments</category>
        
        <category>parkour</category>
        
        
        <category>pcos</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Oh this blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;1.) I learned the hard way that ideas are useless if you can’t get them across. A wise and awesome person once told me I don’t express myself well  because I have a fear of being wrong. So, this blog is my baby step. I find I’m not so paralyzed about being wrong on the internet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) I came across and finished reading through my old journal this week and had a blast laughing and cringing at my past entries. But I also liked how each one was like a screen cap of my past self. It made me appreciate how much I’ve grown as a person. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.) Sometimes when I feel unsure or alone about things I’m going through, I turn to Google. Even when no solutions are presented, reading through and relating to what someone else has gone through has helped me a lot. I’m grateful for the brave souls out there who can put such things to words and up online. Even when it’s something as silly as going shampoo-free. So I’ll try my best to be open here about things I’m shy or fear being wrong about. That’s the point of starting this whole thing. But if someone comes across my writing and it happens to help them in anyway, then by default this blog will have been worth my while. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.) Kung hei, kung hei. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 20:48:20 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/2015/02/19/oh-this-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/2015/02/19/oh-this-blog.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
