<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Your awesome title</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 12:59:04 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 12:59:04 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Oh this blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;1.) I learned the hard way that ideas are useless if you can’t get them across. A wise and awesome person once told me I don’t express myself well  because I have a fear of being wrong. So, this blog is my baby step. I find I’m not so paralyzed about being wrong on the internet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) I came across and finished reading through my old journal this week and had a blast laughing and cringing at my past entries. But I also liked how each one was like a screen cap at my past self. It made me appreciate how much I’ve grown as a person. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3.) Sometimes when I feel unsure or alone about things I’m going through, I turn to Google. Even when no solutions are presented, reading through and relating to what someone else has gone through has helped me a lot. I’m grateful for the brave souls out there who can put such things to words and up online. Even when it’s something as silly as going shampoo-free. So I’ll try my best to be open here about things I’m shy or fear being wrong about. That’s the point of starting this whole thing. But if someone comes across my writing and it happens to help them in anyway, then by default this blog will have been worth my while. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4.) Kung hei, kung hei. :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 20:48:20 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/blog/2015/02/19/oh-this-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/blog/2015/02/19/oh-this-blog.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
